A Guide to the Celia Thaxter Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #6994-e
Celia Thaxter Collection 1874-1892
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
6994-e
10 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase 1968 Sep 3
Item Listing
- Manscript
  - Poem, " The Kaiserblumen ", n. d.; AMsS, 3 p.
- Letters
  - Celia Thaxter, Portsmouth, to Mrs. Sargent, 1874 Jan 8; ALS, 2 p.
    [Regrets delay in returning letter of invitation due to illness of her mother necessitating her spending the winter at the Shoals; requests name of "unknown friend."]
  - Celia Thaxter, Appledore, to [Mary Mapes ?] Dodge, 1874 Oct 11; ALS, 1 p.
    [Inquires about sum sent the previous day, fearing it was not enough.]
  - Celia Thaxter, Appledore, Isle of Shoals, to Mr. Alden, 1875 May 29; ALS, 1 p.
    [Offers poems written in memory of friends lost in the wreck of the ill fated Schiller for publication in his magazine, requests their return if not used.]
  - Celia Thaxter, Newtonville, [James Ripley] Osgood, 1876 Sep 23; ALS, 1 p.
    [Writes that she would like to bring collection of poems and design for book for inspection; hopes to publish by Christmas; asks about financial terms.]
  - Celia Thaxter, Winthrop House, Boston, to Mrs. Thorndike, 1882 Oct 14; ALS, 1 p.
    [Regrets the jar she painted did not turn out as she would like; states that, as soon as she is settled for the winter, she will paint another.]
  - Celia Thaxter, Portsmouth, to Mr. Wingate, 1891 Nov 26; ALS, 1 p.
    [Asks return, for changes and additions, of the letter she sent in response to his request for her choice of [John Greenleaf] Whittier's best poems.]
  - Celia Thaxter, Shoals, to Miss Wheildon, 1892 Mar 20; ALS, 2 p.
    [Thanks her for plants which arrived in perfect condition; requests information on their habit.]
- Miscellaneous
  - Signed receipt for $15 in payment for " Song, " to be published January, 1876, in Scribner's Monthly, from Celia Thaxter to Scribner & Co., 1875 Dec 24; Receipt
  - Celia Thaxter, Portsmouth, New Hampshire, to Mary C. Day, San Luis Obispo, California, 1883 Sep [8 ?]; Envelope